<article xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://jats.nlm.nih.gov/publishing/1.1/xsd/JATS-journalpublishing1-mathml3.xsd" dtd-version="1.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">AAV</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Advances in Acoustics and Vibration</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="epub">1687-627X</issn><issn pub-type="ppub">1687-6261</issn><publisher><publisher-name>Hindawi Publishing Corporation</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="other">2008.350943</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2008/350943</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">350943</article-id><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Editorial</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Active Noise Control</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" id="U38196095" corresp="yes"><name><surname>Pawelczyk</surname><given-names>Marek</given-names></name><xref ref-type="aff" rid="I1" /></contrib></contrib-group><aff id="I1"><addr-line>Institute of Automatic Control</addr-line><addr-line>Silesian University of Technology</addr-line><addr-line>Akademicka 16 Street</addr-line><addr-line>44-101 Gliwice</addr-line><country>Poland</country><ext-link ext-link-type="domain-name">polsl.pl</ext-link></aff><pub-date pub-type="publication-year"><year>2008</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="archival-date"><day>17</day><month>06</month><year>2008</year></pub-date><volume>2008</volume><history><date date-type="received"><day>16</day><month>06</month><year>2008</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>16</day><month>06</month><year>2008</year></date></history><permissions><copyright-year>2008</copyright-year><copyright-holder>Copyright &#xA9; 2008</copyright-holder><license xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/"><license-p>This is an open access article distributed under the Creative Commons Attribution License, which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work is properly cited.</license-p></license></permissions><counts><ref-count count="0" /><page-count count="2" /></counts></article-meta></front><body><p>Active noise control generally aims at reducing an unwanted and unpleasant sound referred to
as the noise. The general idea is very simple. However, there are many problems
related to the acoustic phenomena as well as control limitations. Thus, the
problem is still exciting and attracts attention of a number of scientists
originating from different scientific disciplines. Rapid development of
technology and extensive research allow for manufacturing sensors and actuators
of more advantegous properties, designing more robust and effective algorithms,
and finally performing succesful applications in different noise
pollutted areas.</p><p>The aim of the special issue is just to present recent advances in active noise control
and its applications. I would like to thank all the authors who accepted my
invitation and decided to share their work with a wide circle of readers, what
the open-access journal offers. The papers published in this issue were
peer-reviewed by independent experts. I appreciate help of the experts very
much. Even four reviews per paper where made. Therefore, the eight papers which
are finally included in the issue are of very high quality. Below I am barely
announcing main topics discussed in the issue.</p><p>A novel audiointegrated approach to achieving active
noise control for incubators is proposed by L. Liu et al. The system reduces
excessive broadband noise in neonatal care units and in incubators, which is
generally due to ventillation or breathing equipment. Therefore, the system
tries to protect against auditory damage to preterm infants both due to
short-term and long-term effects. At the same time, the system recreates
prenatal ambience for premature infants. In particular, an efficient robust
nonlinear FXLMS-based adaptive control algorithm is presented. It allows for
stable operation of the ANC system in the presence of impulsive interference in
the input.</p><p>An integrated control system is designed by L. Wang et al. to
improve bass reproduction of the audio equippment and cancel engine noise in
the cabins of automobiles. The problem is difficult because of the frequency
overlap of the bass audio sound and engine noise. On the other hand, small
volume of the cabin and poor low-frequency performance of loudspeakers need
special approach. The proposed system equalizes the engine-noise harmonics
based on the bass information to enhance the low-frequency part of the audio
signal. The system responses also to variations of engine-noise frequencies.
Multifrequency approaches to active noise equalization with frequency-sampling
filters are used.</p><p>A system with a pair of loudspeakers is designed by D.
Bismor to create a virtual unidirectional sound source. It enables successful
cancellation of the acoustic feedback effect and, if supplemented by an active control
system, efficient cancellation of the acoustic noise propagating downstream.
Both fixed parameter and adaptive solutions are used. In the latter case, the
problem of a hazard in tuning the virtual unidirectional sound source and
active noise control algorithm is disclosed and guidelines for scheduling those
operations are given. The overall system has been validated for noise control
in an acoustic duct.</p><p>An active noise control system with online modelling of
time-varying acoustic paths is designed by J. Yuan. Contrary to most publications, any
external signal and thus persistent excitation is not required. Instead,
orthogonal adaptation is used to cancel the acoustic feedback in order to
recover the reference signal. The proposed system&#x2019;s behavior is stable and
converges quickly even in case of significant and rapid changes of the acoustic
path inside a duct.</p><p>A Hinf optimal control system with a pair of
loudspeakers is proposed by Y. Kobayashi and H. Fujioka. As a fixed parameter
solution it requires significantly less computations than an adaptive solution
and still recovers benefits of the Swinbanks&#x2019; source. However, by considering
the pair of loudspeakers as two independent actuators, it gives more
flexibility and better noise control results are possible. The system is
suitable for ventilation ducts in houses.</p><p>A modification of the FXLMS algorithm is proposed by S. P. Lovstedt et al. in order to compensate
for its frequency dependent convergence behavior, which is particularly severe
for plants responding with high peaks and deep valleys. Magnitude of the
frequency response of the secondary path model is modified using a genetic
algorithm to equalize eigenvalues of the autocorrelation matrix of the
filtered-reference signal, while preserving phase of the frequency response of
the model. As a result, higher attenuation and faster convergence are observed.
In the experiments, swept tone noise and multiple tone noise, important in
terms of many practical applications, are considered.</p><p>An active sound intensity probe consisting of a sound hard tube terminated
by aloudspeaker and equipped with a pair of microphones is designed by T. Kletschkowski and D.Sachau. Active control
techniques are used to generate acoustic free field conditions in the tube.
Thus, the probe acts as a local sound absorber and therefore the effect of the
device on a source is reduced. The probe can be used for sound source
localization, especially in weakly damped interior noise fields at low
frequencies.</p><p>A state-feedback control system is proposed by V. Lhuillier et al. in
order to reduce sound transmission through a panel excited by an acoustic wave.
The effect of decreasing eigen frequencies of high-radiation modes and thus
reducing vibration amplitudes at resonance frequencies by adding active modal
masses is used. This effect can also be considered as virtual transformations
of structures that can be used in the field of sound quality.</p><p>I believe that this special issue will
be found interesting by the active noise control community.</p><p content-type="signature-group"><named-content content-type="signature">Marek Pawelczyk</named-content></p></body><back /></article>